Roméo KONÉ

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Passionate by technologies of information, I'm looking for opportunities that will take me out of my comfort zone...

I have spent more than a decade as a software engineer, involved in designing, developing, and maintaining software applications. My expertise lies in software engineering methodologies, software design, and the entire software development life cycle.

About

CONTACT

Lot. Le Point du jour 96 rue de la Biguine Terreville

97233 SCHOELCHER, France

(+33)609426639

romeo.kone@outlook.com

EDUCATION

EPITECH Paris

- 2015 Master in Technologies of Information
- 2013 Bachelor

ESAM-Vridi, Abidjan

2009 BTCE HND in Industrial Computing and Maintenance

SKILLS

Java EE, NodeJS, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML/CSS, C/C++, MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQLite, H2, MariaDB, SQL Server, Spring, Kubernetes, Angular, React, Git, Docker, Gradle, Maven, Android, JPA, IntelliJ IDEA, Jenkins, Jolt, Strapi, Vavr, Helm, Keycloak, WSO2 IDP, Visual Studio Code, Sonar, Strapi, Junit, Selenium, Mockito, Cucumber, SVN, Eclipse, Emacs, RabbitMQ, Android, Elastic Search, GitLab, Bitbucket, Qt, Aws, Azure, Windows, Linux, MacOS Bash/Shell, PowerShell, Agile Scrum, SAFe

LANGUAGES

French

English

Work Experience

TEAM TECHNICAL LEADER, SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Lexis Nexis Risk Solutions (Fircosoft) | Since July 2018

- Developed multiples micro-services for a watchlist update manager solution to improve list management process
- · Managed and Lead a squad in best practices
- · Implemented and maintained CI/CD pipelines
- · Implemented scalable architecture for performance and cloud needs
- · Delivered products into the cloud and supported customer

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT

Fircosoft (via Palo IT) | October 2016 - June 2018

- Created and implemented real-time monitoring and control of all stages of compliance and configuration operations to reduce alerts during filtering.
- Collaborated with cross teams to ensure design, architecture, security and user experience alignment
- · Implemented SSO authentication via SAML
- Implemented an administration service for users, permissions, JWT, licenses, management

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT

SACEM (via Palo IT) | September 2014 - October 2016

- Developed the new version the sacem.fr portal, which is intended to be the single point of entry for all its audiences.
- Implemented features for Members to manage their account (history, referenced works, invoices, etc.).
- · Set up a shopping basket and payments, modelled and generated invoices
- · Delivered and Maintained

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT

AS24 by Total Energies (via Palo IT) | August - September 2014

 Implemented, Deployed mobile app for truck fleet managers to help them geolocate and provide enhanced services at service stations

CO-FOUNDER, TECHNICAL MANAGER

Innogen | March 2014 - March 2016

- Created the company "Innogen" and developed HairGen, a software program that lets you try out haircuts in real time.
- Set up a continuous integration system